A Guide to the Indochina Arts Partnership records FA1849
Rockefeller Archive Center
Indochina Arts Partnership records
1970-2019
Rockefeller Archive Center
Indochina Arts Partnership
C. David Thomas
FA1849
5.3 Cubic Feet 10 containers: 4 letter document boxes, 5 legal document boxes, and one record storage box.
Arrangement
As received.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The Indochina Arts Partnership records were donated to the RAC by C. David Thomas in 2019.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC. Researchers interested in accessing digital media (floppy disks, CDs, DVDs, etc.) in this collection must use an access surrogate. The original items may not be accessed because of preservation concerns. To request an access surrogate be made, or if you are unsure if there is an access surrogate, please contact an archivist.
When requesting to view audiovisual material, please refer to the Title and the AV Number (example: AV 1916). Researchers are asked to check the "Restrictions" note for each Title. If a Title does not currently have an access copy, please contact a RAC archivist for further instruction.
Scope and Contents
The Indochina Arts Partnership records contain exhibit information, exhibit agreements, slides, photographs, audiovisual material, and books detailing the work of the Partnership from its inception in 1987 to its closing in 2019. The collection details the various exhibits that were curated by the Indochina Arts Partnership including Seven Pillars: The National Treasure Artists of Vietnam, As Seen by Both Sides, and An Ocean Apart. Also included throughout the records is information about C. David Thomas, the founder of the Indochina Arts Partnership.
Arts -- Vietnam; Vietnam War, 1961-1975; Vietnam War, 1961-1975 -- Veterans
- Seven Pillars - IAP Loan Agreements, undated (Box 1, Folder 1-7)
- Seven Pillars - IAP Loan Agreements, Negative, Contact Sheets, undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Seven Pillars - Price per Painting, undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Seven Pillars - Museum Correspondence, 1996-1998 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Seven Pillars - Essays, undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Seven Pillars - Background Information, undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Seven Pillars - Slides, undated (Box 2, Folder 13-19)
- Seven Pillars - Slides, undated (Box 3, Folder 20-21)
- Seven Pillars - Contact Sheets, undated (Box 3, Folder 22-23)
- Seven Pillars - Transparencies, undated (Box 3, Folder 24-26)
- Seven Pillars - Transparencies, undated (Box 4, Folder 27)
- National Heritage Board, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 28)
- An Ocean Apart - Smithsonian Institution Traveling Exhibition Service, 1997-1998 (Box 4, Folder 29)
- Essays, undated (Box 4, Folder 30)
- As Seen by Both Sides: American and Vietnamese Artists Look at the War, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 31)
- As Seen by Both Sides: Articles and Reviews, 1990 May-1994 June (Box 4, Folder 32)
- As Seen by Both Sides: Reviews and Articles from the First Seven Venues, 1990-1992 (Box 4, Folder 33)
- As Seen by Both Sides - Scrapbook, 1989-1991 (Box 5, Folder 34-35)
- As Seen by Both Sides - Transparencies, undated (Box 5, Folder 36-39)
- As Seen by Both Sides - Photographs, 1991-1992 (Box 5, Folder 40)
- An Ocean Apart - Articles, 1996-1997 (Box 5, Folder 41)
- Web References, 2017-2019 (Box 5, Folder 42)
- Articles and Clippings, 1970-1990 (Box 6, Folder 43)
- Articles and Clippings, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 44)
- Articles and Clippings, 1992-1993 (Box 6, Folder 45)
- Articles and Clippings, 1994-1999 (Box 6, Folder 46)
- Articles and Clippings, 2000 (Box 6, Folder 47)
- Articles and Clippings, 2001-2006 (Box 6, Folder 48)
- Articles and Clippings, 2007-2008; 2010 (Box 6, Folder 49)
- Articles and Clippings, 1988-1991; undated (Box 7, Folder 50)
- Articles and Clippings, 1991-2003; undated (Box 7, Folder 51)
- Articles and Clippings, 1996-2003; undated (Box 7, Folder 52)
- Articles and Clippings - C. David Thomas, 1976; undated (Box 7, Folder 53)
- Articles and Clippings - Huynh Phuong Dong Book, 2006 (Box 7, Folder 54)
- Articles and Photographs - Ho Chi Minh: A Portrait, 2003-2015 (Box 7, Folder 55)
- An Ocean Apart: Contemporary Vietnamese Art from the United States and Vietnam, 1995 (Box 7, Folder 56)
- Both Sides Now, Boston Sunday Herald, 1991 January 13 (Box 9, Folder 57)
- Goodbye Siagon, Weekend, Rocky Mountain News, 1990 May 25 (Box 9, Folder 58)
- Building Bridges, Weekend, MetroWest Daily News, 2012 April 5 (Box 9, Folder 59)
- Artistic Ambassador, The Daily News, 2002 May 26 (Box 9, Folder 60)
- Remembering Ho Chi Minh, Newton Tab, 2000 August 24 (Box 9, Folder 61)
- Ho Chi Minh sign, undated (Box 9, Folder 62)
- Ho Chi Minh Haters, AsianWeek, 2000 March 30-April 5 (Box 9, Folder 63)
- Art New England, 1996-1997 (Box 9, Folder 64)
- Huynh Phuong Dong: Visions of War and Peace, 2007 (Box 9)
- Hanoi Streets 1985-2015: In the Years of Forgetting, 2018 (Box 9)
- The Daily Arts (The Arts and Cultures of Viet Nam: A Journey Through History), Phan Cam Thuong, 2014 (Box 8)
- Art in Times of War / Nghe Thuat Thoi Chien Tranh, Francisco de Goya y Lucientes, 2008 (Box 8)
- C. David Thomas: Four Decades of Making Art, 1969-2009, undated (Box 8)
- Le Lam: Sketches from the South, Bùi Như Hương, 2015 (Box 8)
- Indochina Arts Partnership: Thirty-two Years of Building Bridges, 1987-2019 (Box 8)
- Indochina Arts Partnership, 1988-2012, undated (Box 8)
- Camouflage: Vietnamese Brushstrokes with History (Box 8)
  Conditions Governing Access
  Researchers interested in accessing digital media (floppy disks, CDs, DVDs, etc.) in this collection must use an access surrogate. The original items may not be accessed because of preservation concerns. To request an access surrogate be made, or if you are unsure if there is an access surrogate, please contact an archivist.
- An Opportunity Was Lost (Box 8)
- The 1994 Hanoi Interview with Artist Nguyen Tu Nghiem (Box 8)
- The 1994 Interview with Artist Tran Van Can (Box 8)
- Họa sĩ Lê Huy Tiếp (Box 8)
- At the Library with Beth Purcell, 2000; VHS (Box 1, Tape AV 13106)
  Open for research. Digital access copy currently unavailable. Please contact a RAC archivist for further instruction.
  Scope and Contents
  Guests: Natalie Schatz and C. David ThomaS. Produced at the NewTV, Newton, Massachusetts
- Opening of Exhibition HCMC, Spring, 1993 December 29; VHS (Box 1, Tape AV 13107)
- Trip to Vietnam (full tape), Nqhicm at end, 1992 July; VHS (Box 1, Tape AV 13108)
- Tran Van Can Interview, Hanoi (Master Copy), 1992 August; VHS (Box 1, Tape AV 13109)
- As Seen by Both Sides - Atlanta Panel Discussion, 1993 February 3; VHS (Box 1, Tape AV 13110)
- HOA in BCC (Master), circa 1990s; VHS (Box 1, Tape AV 13111)
- WQTV Inner City Beat: "B.U. Art Show", 1991 February 11; VHS (Box 1, Tape AV 13112)
- From Both Sides - Newton Cable, 20 May 1992; VHS (Box 1, Tape AV 13113)
  Thomas interview on Newton Cable about ASBS and print exhibit.
- WCVB "B.U. Art Show/War Memories", 1991 January 14; VHS (Box 1, Tape AV 13114)
- Opening Rec ASBS - HCUM, 1994 May 23; Hi8 (Box 1, Tape AV 13115)